PERSONAL INFORMATION

Leonard Mrima Jembe

• Mombasa, Kenya

= +254 718950469

™ mrimajay1@gmail.com

Sex Male | Date of birth 10/12/1994 | Nationality Kenyan

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Professional chemist with more than three years of experience in the field and a strong working knowledge of the industry.

Excellent command of the English language, including oral and written comprehension skills. Critical thinker who is reliable, responsible, organize, and always goes the extra mile for the job

WORK EXPERIENCE

June 2017 - Sept 2017

Attachment

Ministry of Health

Government Chemist's Department, Mombasa

Branch, KENYA

Responsibilities and achievements: I trained

and assisted in:

- ✓ Good laboratory practice and safety
- ✓ Full chemical analysis of water, including instrumental and wet chemistry methods
- ✓ Effluent analysis: Chemical Oxygen Demand, Biochemical Oxygen demand and Total Dissolved Solids
- ✓ Food analysis and Drugs analysis including determination of proteins, fats, sugars, aflatoxins, ash and moisture, acidity and rancidity
- ✓ Microbiological analysis of Foods and Water.
- ✓ General instrumental methods of analysis including Gas Liquid Chromatography, GC-Ms, AAS, UV/Visible Spectroscopy
- ✓ Human Identification (DNA extraction and DNA profile)
- ✓ Housekeeping.

Sept 2017- Aug 2018

Quality Control Analyst (Internship)

Shreeji Chemicals ltd, Mombasa KENYA.

Responsibilities and achievements:

- ✓ Performed visual inspections of final products to ensure they met all desired criteria in the initial blueprints.
- ✓ Received raw materials for production processes to ensure they met company's high standards
- ✓ Filled out documents, presented findings to employer and filled those documents into digital bookkeeping system once findings were accepted and implemented
- ✓ Maintain laboratory and its equipment, troubleshooting issues when necessary to ensure a safe and productive lab.

Jan 2019- Feb 2021

Quality Control analyst at Salwa Kenya Limited.

Responsibilities and achievements:

- ✓ Maintain inventory and purchased laboratory supplies when necessary including chemicals, beakers, test tubes and equipment.
- ✓ Preparing reagents and test solutions in order to conduct laboratory tests
- ✓ Inspecting pack materials to ensure are conforming with standards
- ✓ Ensuring raw materials and Final products are complying with specifications as per Standard operating procedures.
- ✓ Writing reports and technical papers detailing processes, tests and products.

February 2021-

Senior Quality Control Analyst (EDIBLES) at Pwani Oil Products Responsibilities and achievements:

- ✓ Controlling the refining process from raw materials to final products.
- ✓ Giving directions and making decisions for the refinery operators on the required parameters for the refining process that impacts end products Quality.
- ✓ Preparing and standardizing of bench reagents for lab use.
- ✓ Teaching of new employees and attaches' on managing Quality laboratories.

EDUCATION

Masinde Muliro University of Science and Technology 2017

Bachelors of Science in Chemistry

Dr Krapf Memorial Secondary School-Rabai 2012

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (KCSE)

St Martins Primary School-Kilifi 2008

Kenya Certificate of Primary Education (*KCPE*)

PERSONAL SKILLS

- ✓ Exceptional communicator who has the ability to convey and understand complex thoughts in person or via writing
- ✓ Patient instructor who has the knowledge of teaching methods that helps new employees, interns, and others to learn how to properly conduct analyses in laboratory environment.
- ✓ Qualified chemist who has the dexterity and coordination to work in laboratory with expensive equipment and dangerous chemicals
- ✓ Outstanding critical thinker who can use logic and reasoning to identify weaknesses in laboratory and find solution to the weakness.

INTERESTS & ACTIVITIES —

- ✓ I enjoy reading about history and travelling. I have travelled extensively around my country.
- ✓ I am greatly interested in technological exploration and learning new advancements.

1. Mr Simon Mrombo

Pwani Oil Products Limited

HOD Quality Department-Edibles

Cell: (+254) 720758179

2. Mr. Karisa Kazungu

Salwa Kenya Limited

Quality Manager

Cell: (+254) 721232258

3. Mrs. Teresia Luttah

HOD Quality Control Department

Shreeji Chemicals Ltd

Cell: (+254) 726486928